With a suitcase full of song, Hearts filled with passion, two
brothers come to America in search of a dream.
The Mambo Kings is a drama, music film directed by Arne Glimcher.
The Mambo Kings tells the story of César and Nestor Castillo, brothers and aspiring
musicians who flee from Cuba to America in search of the American Dream.
Nestor Castillo, played by Antonio Banderas.
Cesar Castillo, played by Armand Assante.
Lanna Lake, played by Cathy Moriarty.
Delores Fuentes, played by Maruschka Detmers.
Ramon - The Mambo Kings Band, played by Pablo Calogero.
Bernardito - The Mambo Kings Band, played by Scott Cohen.
The Mambo Kings is a 1992 musical drama film based on the 1989 Pulitzer
Prize-winning novel The Mambo Kings Play Songs of Love by Oscar Hijuelos.
The film was directed and produced by Arne Glimcher, and stars Armand
Assante, Antonio Banderas, Cathy Moriarty and Maruschka Detmers.
Set in the early 1950s, the story follows Cesar (Assante) and Nestor Castillo (Banderas), brothers and aspiring
musicians who find success and stardom after fleeing from Havana, Cuba to New York City to escape danger.
The film marks Glimcher's directing debut, and features
Banderas in his first English-language role.
Glimcher acquired the film rights one year before the novel was
published and hired Cynthia Cidre to write the script.
The film was rejected by several studios, and after an unsuccessful
pre-production at Universal Pictures, the project moved to Warner Bros.
The production was allocated a budget of $15.5 million jointly financed by
Warner Bros., Le Studio Canal+ and Regency Enterprises.
The film was shot on location in Los Angeles, California, with principal
photography beginning in March 1991, and concluding after 50 days.
The Mambo Kings premiered at the Miami International
Film Festival on February 7, 1992.
It opened in limited release on February 28, 1992, and grossed $6.7
million during its North American theatrical run.
Critical reaction was mostly positive, with reviewers praising
Glimcher's direction, the story, music and visuals.
The film received Oscar, Golden Globe Award and Grammy nominations
for its original song "Beautiful Maria of My Soul".
The tone is emotional.